A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Arts and Humanities Program Files, Marcia T. Thompson FA1482
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Arts and Humanities Program Files, Marcia T. Thompson
1954-1999
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
Thompson, Marcia
FA1482
22.3 Cubic Feet 56 boxes total (45 letter document containers and 11 legal document containers)
Biographical / Historical
Marcia Aldrich Thompson Thompson (1923-2018) was an advocate for financial stabilization projects in the arts throughout her long career with the Ford Foundation, the National Arts Stabilization Fund, and as a board member for many arts organizations. She was born on Oct. 2, 1923 in Hankow, China. Thompson attended the Columbia University School of General Studies, the New School for Social Research, and earned a certificate from Katherine Gibbs School. She started her career at the New York Times as the Assistant to the Sunday Editor from 1946-1951. She moved on to hold multiple positions at the International Press Institute as Assistant to the Chairman and Associate Director, Conference Coordinator until 1953. In 1955, she married Ralph Thompson, a book critic and columnist for the New York Times, and secretary of the Book‐of‐the-Month Club.
In 1953, Thompson joined the Ford Foundation as a program officer. From the beginning, she was involved in the formation and development of the Foundation's program in humanities and the arts. She had a hand in all major subsequent initiatives through 1983, including the development of programs for individual artists as well as institutional development in the arts. She worked to create incentives for symphonies, ballet companies, theaters and other arts groups to liquidate their deficits and build working capital reserves. Some of her achievements include: providing $80.2 million in grants to orchestras across the country as part of the Symphony Orchestra Program, providing support for development of dance companies and professional training in classical dance, and developing the Program for Administrative Interns, the Program for Curatorial Training, and the Program for Catalogues of American Fine Arts Collections. She also led the Ford Foundation Cash Reserve Program from which the National Arts Stabilization Fund eventually evolved. She collaborated closely with Ford Foundation executive William W. McPeak and Vice President W. McNeil Lowry. Lowry and Thompson's partnership helped Ford become the country's largest nongovernmental arts patron and the first to support dance. By 1967, Thompson was the Ford Foundation's senior program officer in the arts and humanities.
Thompson left the Ford Foundation to found and serve as president of the National Arts Stabilization Fund (NASF) in December 1983. The NASF was created with funding from the Ford Foundation, the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation, and the Rockefeller Foundation, to provide arts institutions with grants and fiscal management strategies. Thompson was responsible for all aspects of the NASF's operations including development of principles and policies, fundraising, project development and oversight, administration, planning, board relations and external affairs until 1991. She served as Chairman of the Executive Committee and Vice Chairman of the NASF from 1991-1993. Thompson was also a board member of the School of American Ballet, Theater for a New Audience and the Scherman Foundation. Marcia Thompson died in March 2018.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into eight series:
1. Grants and Administrative Files, 1954-1999
2. Symphony Orchestra Program (SOP), 1953-1988
3. Cash Reserve Program, 1965-1987
4. National Arts Stabilization Fund (NASF), 1970-1994
5. Ford Foundation Board of Trustees, 1955-1992
6. Humanities and the Arts Program Files, 1953-1986
7. Ford Foundation Stabilization Program, 1971-1993
8. Education and Culture Program, 1956-1985
Scope and Contents
The collection contains the office files of Marcia T. Thompson, former program officer in the Office of the Humanities and the Arts at the Ford Foundation. Contents include background papers, reports, correspondence, grant files, and materials relating to the Symphony Orchestra Program, the Cash Reserve Program, the Ford Stabilization Program, the Office of the Humanities and the Arts, the Education and Culture Program, and the National Arts Stabilization Fund (NASF).
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by the RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary. This material was transferred to the RAC in 2018 by the Ford Foundation and was ingested by the RAC as Accession 2018:131.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Related Materials
Marcia T. Thompson papers (FA1489)
Ford Foundation; Humanities -- United States; Program development -- Arts -- Ford Foundation; Symphony orchestras -- United States
- Grants and Administrative Files, 1954-1999; 1
  Scope and Contents
  Correspondence, memos, reports, news clippings, office files, and grant materials
  - Center for Applied Linguistics FY1967 - FY1970, 1970 November (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Grant Making: A Study of the Process for Reaching Decisions on Grants, A Report to the President of the Ford Foundation, 1973 November 19 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Mary Brucker, Merrimon Cuninggim, Advisors
  - News from the Ford Foundation, 1977 May 11 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Interoffice Memos Regarding Report on Grant Decision-Making, 1973 November-December (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Economic and Social Positions of the Artist and His Institutions, Phase I: Descriptive and Statistical, 1958 April 8 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Section 1: The Visual Arts
    Section 2: Music
    Section 3: The Theatre Arts
    Section 4: The Dance
    Section 5: Creative Writing Other Than Dramatic
  - Modern Dance Companies with Expense Budgets of $500,000 or Less in 1970-71, 1973 March 12 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Evaluation Study: The Ford Foundation Program for Administrative Interns, 1974 September 10 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Outlines - Local Letter Agreement Binder, Charitable Giving Statistics and Trends, Operating Statistics in the Arts, 1994 January (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - The Ford Foundation and "Dependent" Organizations - 1971/Covers of Ford Internal Information Papers, 1967-1983 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Financial Planning Priorities, 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Joffrey Ballet - 1983
    Theatre Communications Group - 1983
    The Feld Ballet - 1983
    Lyric Opera of Chicago - 1984
    School of the American Ballet - 1985
    Principles and Policies List
  - Does Industry Need Art Schools?, 1969 June 24 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Attachment of Rob Roy Kelly's letter of 6/24/69
  - Action - Interoffice Memos, 1976-1991 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Interoffice Memos Regarding Personnel, 1971-1983 (Box 55, Folder 455)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Sensitive Material
  - Leonard R. Vignola (3 folders), 1972-1991 (Box 1, Folder 13, Box 2, Folder 14-15)
    Memos and correspondence
  - Boston Project - 1985 Announcement, Awards, Letters of Comment (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 16-17)
    Includes:
    Press Release
    Coverage Release
    Letters of Comment
  - Worthy of Note (newspaper clippings), 1972-1988 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Literary Classics, Library of America, 1971-1983 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Thompson, Ralph, 1964-1976 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    National Translation Center
  - Lowry, W. McNeil (2 folders), 1965-1975 (Box 2, Folder 21-22)
  - Grants, Program Officer Marcia Thompson, 2013 December 11 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    List from the Rockefeller Archive Center
  - Marcia T. Thompson - Ford Foundation Oral History Agreement and Transcripts, 1974 August 16 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Marcia Thompson - Research and Questionnaires, 1981 January (Box 2, Folder 25)
    Also includes research printouts from the Rockefeller Archive Center
  - Policy on Rotation of Senior Foundation Officers, 1973 April 11 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Alternative Futures: Challenging Designs for Arts Philanthropy, A Series of Conference Papers Exploring Arts and Philanthropy in the United States Today, Commissioned by Grantmakers in the Arts, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Leverage Lost: The Nonprofit Arts in the Post-Ford Era, John Kreidler, 1995 December (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous Documents, 1985-1999 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    Index to W. McNeil Lowry Speeches, Articles, Congressional Testimonies, Etc.
    List of appearances in articles, at conferences, as an awardee
    W. McNeil Lowry papers (from the University of Illinois Archives) finding aid printout
    Letters from Talton F. Ray
  - M. Thompson's Rolodex - Business Cards, Cards from Richmond AAM Meeting (2 folders), 1986 October (Box 3, Folder 30-31)
  - Materials for Marcia Thompson Visit, 1980-1990 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    Visit to the Rockefeller Archive Center
  - School of American Ballet - Grant Report, 1969-1984 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Letters to Save, 1991-2014 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Blumenfeld, Helaine, 1982-1988 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    Art catalogs
  - Opera, 1978-1990 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    Correspondence and 1989-90 Season's Projection Per Opera America (Profile 1989)
  - Museums, 1985-1989 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Theaters, 1984-1986 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Foundation for Hellenic Culture, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - San Francisco Symphony Association to Honor the Generosity of the Ford Foundation - Dinner, 1967 May 9 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    Includes remarks, programs, newspaper clippings, and photographs
  - Noteworthy Correspondence (2 folders), 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 41-42)
  - Literary Classics - Poetry and Small Press Publications (3 folders), 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 43-45)
  - Background Papers for Common Fund Meeting, 1966-1973 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    Contents:
    1. Press Release of 7/6/66 - 10-year grant $80.2 million Symphony Orchestra Program
    2. Terms of Grant
    3. Trust Agreement
    4. Summary of Matching Achieved as of 6/30/71
    5. Letter of 6/1/72
    6. Leter of 9/1/72
    7. Letter of 8/1/73
    8. Statistics Fiscal 1971
    9. Statistics Fiscal 1972
    10. Annual Internal Review Form
  - National Endowment for the Arts (NEA), 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Washington, DC - Consortium, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Theater Directors Program, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Juilliard School: Drama Division (2 folders), 1978 (Box 5, Folder 50-51)
  - Mellon - Debt Reduction Analysis - Orchestras, 1972-1977 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - National Symphony Orchestra, 1972-1977 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - The Ford Foundation Ballet Development - FY 1959-1971, 1980 May (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - New York City Opera Grant of $2.6 Million, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - New American Theater Development, 1978-1982 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Broadway Theaters FY 1970-1977 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - The Ford Foundation Program for Catalogues of Fine Arts Collections (2 folders), 1977 September 30 (Box 6, Folder 58-59)
  - Patronage and Pluralism, 1977 January-April (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Mellon Drafts FY 1976-1984 (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Opera Forms, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Memorandum for the Officers from McGeorge Bundy, 1976-1977 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Mailing Lists, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Ford Foundation Information (General), 1966-1977 (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Internal Memos (2 folders), 1982-1993 (Box 6, Folder 66-67)
  - Filmmakers, 1963-1976 (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - Marcia T. Thompson (MTT) Chrons, 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Marcia T. Thompson (MTT) Chrons, 1983 September 1-October 31 (Box 7, Folder 70)
  - Ruder and Finn/Public Interest Public Relations Firm (PIPRF) - Temporary File, 1973-1976 (Box 7, Folder 71)
  - Economic and Financial Survey - Case Histories, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 72)
  - Economic and Financial Survey, Draft - Historical Introduction, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 73)
  - Lucille Graham - Job Description Program, 1956 March 30 (Box 7, Folder 74)
  - Administrative Interns - Reports (3 folders), 1973-1974 (Box 7, Folder 75-77)
  - Museums (2 folders), 1968-1976 (Box 7, Folder 78, Box 8, Folder 79)
    For 11/19 meeting
  - Greek Grants and Notes, 1972-1975 (Box 8, Folder 80)
  - Background/Theater, 1959-1976 (Box 8, Folder 81)
  - School of American Ballet - Evaluation, 1963-1973 (Box 8, Folder 82)
  - Best Practices, Examples of, 1967-1968 (Box 8, Folder 83)
    Notes and memos
  - Zeisler, Peter, 1972-1981 (Box 8, Folder 84)
  - Theater - Resident Professional/League of Resident Theatres (LORT) Companies, 1967-1978 (Box 8, Folder 85)
  - Useful Articles, 1963-1970 (Box 8, Folder 86)
    Moving the Rough Road to Home: Reports from readers help you take the bumps; they shed light on 14 van lines
    Arts Management - Lawyers Form New Organization to Aid and Counsel the Arts
  - Cuninggim, Merrimon Reports, 1973-1974 (Box 8, Folder 87)
  - New York Public Library L68-303, 1967-1972 (Box 8, Folder 88)
  - Fellowships and Awards, 1958-1960 (Box 8, Folder 89)
  - Notes on the Principles and Policies of the Ford Foundation - Drafts, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 90)
  - California Giving - The Scherman Foundation, Inc. (3 folders), 1971-1984 (Box 8, Folder 91-93)
  - Theater Communications Group (2 folders), 1970-1972 (Box 9, Folder 94-95)
    Sections include:
    Rank Order List of Theaters by Number of Actos Seen
    Actors Equity
    Administrative Interns
    Arts Councils
    Ballet Development
    Catalogues
    Cultural Activities
    Foundations
    Museum Curatorial Training
    National Endowment for the Arts
    National Endowment for the Humanities
    N.Y. State Council on the Arts
    New York City Ballet
    State Arts Agencies
    Statistics/FF
    Statistics/ H/A
    Tamarind
  - Consultants - Trip Reports/Theater Production Reports (2 folders), 1971-1975 (Box 9, Folder 96-97)
  - Talks by Mercedes Matter - Training the Professional Artist, On Drawing, On Curriculum, 1967 November 22 (Box 9, Folder 98)
  - The Ford Foundation and "Dependent" Organizations: An Information Paper for Discussion by the Trustees at the September 1971 Meeting, 1971 September (Box 9, Folder 99)
  - Roger Kennedy - To Members of the Arts Committee, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 100)
    Memos and Correspondence
    Theater Reawakening: A Report on Ford Foundation Assistance to American Drama
    The Arts in June
  - Roger Kennedy Correspondence, 1977-1979 (Box 9, Folder 101)
  - Ford Foundation Building, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 102)
  - Kendall, Elizabeth - Correspondence, Chronological Order, 1975-1979 (Box 10, Folder 103)
  - Kendall, Elizabeth - Parts of Manuscripts, 1977-1978 (Box 10, Folder 104)
  - Guarnieri, Luciano - Triple Portrait, 1971-1972 (Box 10, Folder 105)
  - Thompson, Franklin A., 1974-1980 (Box 10, Folder 106)
  - Correspondence A-Z (4 folders), 1979 (Box 10, Folder 107-108, Box 11, Folder 109-110)
  - Roger Kennedy's Correspondence L-Z (2 folders), 1977-1978 (Box 11, Folder 111-112)
  - Theater Communications Group (TCG) vs. Ford Foundation vs. Stabilization, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 113)
  - Franklin A. Thomas - Clippings and Press Releases, 1980-1982 (Box 12, Folder 114)
  - O/A Statistics/Theater, 1957-1972 (Box 12, Folder 115)
  - Rueppel Memoranda, 1970-1972 (Box 12, Folder 116)
    Cantor Appt. Letter
    Cantor Report
    Letter Rueppel
    Rueppel Analysis and Tables
  - Interoffice Memoranda (2 folders), 1961-1982 (Box 12, Folder 117-118)
  - Ford Foundation Task Force - Affirmative Action, 1972-1980 (Box 12, Folder 119)
  - Ford Foundation Policy and Procedures: Dependent Organizations, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 120)
  - Proposed Budget and Program for FY 1980-1981, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 121)
  - Marcia Thompson Chrons (2 folders), 1983 January 1-February 28 (Box 13, Folder 122-123)
  - Marcia Thompson Chrons, 1983 May 1-August 31 (Box 13, Folder 124)
  - Marcia Thompson Chrons, 1983 November 1-December 31 (Box 13, Folder 125)
  - Endowment Funds - Barker Reports, Lore of, etc., 1972-1977 (Box 13, Folder 126)
  - Catalogues Program: Status of Grants, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 127)
  - Newman, Danny (2 folders), 1976-1981 (Box 13, Folder 128-129)
  - Vienna Opera, Temporary File, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 130)
  - Kapp, Richard G. Memoranda, 1969-1971 (Box 14, Folder 131)
  - Opera Theatre of St. Louis - 1982 Analysis, 1981-1982 (Box 14, Folder 132)
  - Whither the Arts? Principles, Policies, and Observations (2 folders), 1974-1983 (Box 14, Folder 133-134)
    Includes memos, notes, and correspondence from theater representatives (many letters from/involving Daniel Newman)
  - Gertrude Hooker Memo, 1963 February (Box 55, Folder 456)
    Confidential
  - Verne Atwater Memo - Personnel Policies, 1966 January 27 (Box 14, Folder 135)
  - Ford Foundation Oral History Project - Interview with Marcia Thompson - Edited Transcript and Correspondence, 1973-1975 (Box 14, Folder 136)
  - Pennsylvania Ballet - Memos and Financial Information, 1976-1980 (Box 14, Folder 137)
  - San Francisco Foundation - Buck Trust Suit, 1988-1992 (Box 14, Folder 138)
  - Correspondence and Mailing List (2 folders), 1985-1993 (Box 14, Folder 139-140)
  - American Symphony Orchestra League - Comparative Statistical Report, 1989-1990 Season, Orchestras With Expenses Over $4,700,000, 1990 November (Box 15, Folder 141)
  - American Symphony Orchestra League - 1989-1990 Season - Labor Contract Survey - Orchestras With Expenses Over $2,400,000 (Box 15, Folder 142)
  - Horizon, Volume IV, Number 3 - "Ford Moves in on the Arts, p. 4", 1962 January (Box 15, Folder 143)
  - Ford Foundation Directives and Terms of Reference for the 1960s, 1962 June (Box 15, Folder 144)
  - Ford Catalogues Program Evaluations Published by Museums of Fine Arts (2 folders), 1971-1983 (Box 15, Folder 145-146)
  - Letters of Grant - Other (2 folders), 1974-1979 (Box 15, Folder 147, Box 16, Folder 148)
  - 1. Annexes, 1975 June 19 (Box 16, Folder 149)
    Sections of the publication include:
    Organisation of Cultural Activities in France
    Theatres and Symphony Orchestras in West Germany
    Radio and Television
    Theatres and Symphony Orchestras in Austria
    Great Britain: Official aid to Cultural Activities
    Cultural Activities in the Scandinavian Countries
    Official Theatres in Brussels
    Theatres in Switzerland
    Italy: Opera Houses
    Theatre and Music in Spain
    Theatre and Symphony orchestras in Portugal
  - 2. Federal Germany (starts with), 1975 June 19 (Box 16, Folder 150)
  - 3. Scandinavian Countries (starts with), 1975 June 19 (Box 16, Folder 151)
  - 1. Theatre and Music in Western and Northern Europe, 1960-1972, Subsidies - Administration, Life and Working Conditions of Creative and Performing Artists, Ruby D'Arschot, 1975 June 19 (Box 16, Folder 152)
    Introduction
    The Promotion of theatre and music in France
    Opera and Ballet in Paris
    Symphony Orchestras
    Theatres amd Symphony orchestras in Vienna
    Theatre, Opera, Ballet, and Symphony orchestras in Great Britain
    Symphony Orchestras in London
    Theatres and Symphony Orchestras in Scandinavia
    Orchestras in the Scandinavian Countries
    Theatres and Symphony Orchestras in Amsterdam
    Theatre and Opera in Brussels
    Theatre and Symphony orchestras in Switzerland
    Theatre and Symphony orchestra in Italy
    Theatre and Music in Spain and Portugal
    The Performing Artist
  - 2. Great Britain (starts with), 1975 June 19 (Box 17, Folder 153)
- Symphony Orchestra Program (SOP), 1953-1988; 2
  Biographical / Historical
  From 1966 to 1976, the Ford Foundation contributed over $80 million to 61 symphony orchestras in the United States and Puerto Rico, with dual missions of improving the financial conditions of North American orchestral musicians and strengthening perceptions of American culture in Europe and Asia. The program raised musicians' salaries and helped orchestras develop new fundraising mechanisms.
  - Symphony Orchestra Program (SOP) - Annual Review Memos (2 folders), 1966-1985 (Box 17, Folder 154-155)
  - Symphony Orchestra Program (SOP) - Program Information, 1965-1966 (Box 17, Folder 156)
    Grants - Listing
    Program Papers (Listing)
    Funds - Definitions
    Terms of Grant - Dev.
    Press Release - Oct. 22, 1965
    Press Release - July 6, 1966
    American Symphony Orchestra League Speech -- EFD
  - Symphony Orchestras: Memos and Programs (2 folders), 1961-1982 (Box 17, Folder 157-158)
  - Symphony Orchestra Program - Clippings, Memos Related to Individual Orchestras, Notes Related to Grants, Budget Analysis (5 folders), 1964-1975 (Box 18, Folder 159-163)
    Also includes Questionnaires for Orchestras, The Symphony Orchestra Abroad: A Report of a Study, Howard Taubman
  - Symphony Orchestra Program - Ranked by Size of Endowment Funds, 1970-1973 (Box 18, Folder 164)
  - Tickler for Symphony Orchestra Program, 1965-1982 (Box 18, Folder 165)
  - Symphony Program General Information - News Clippings, Memos, Press Releases, 1965-1966 (Box 18, Folder 166)
  - Symphony Program - News Release and Attachments, 1965 October 22 (Box 19, Folder 167)
    From folder - Editor's Note: This folder contains the announcement of a major program for American symphony orchestras, together with background material.
    -- News Release
    -- Attachment I: Background
    -- Attachment II: American Symphony Orchestra League Lists
    -- Attachment III: Previous Ford Foundation Activities in Music
  - Symphony Orchestra Program - Developmental Funds Report, 1972-1973 (Box 19, Folder 168)
    Memos and budget information related to individual symphonies
  - Symphony Orchestra Program - Materials, 1966-1973 (Box 19, Folder 169)
    Ford Foundation Letter - Special Report: Symphonic Strains (Financial)
    Agreement Between The Ford Foundation and the Bank of New York
    News Release
  - Symphony Orchestra Program - Running Statistics (3 folders), 1972-1980 (Box 19, Folder 170-172)
  - Symphony Orchestras' Data Analysis, 1976-1985 (Box 19, Folder 173)
    Ford National Program for Symphony Orchestras: A Final Report, 1966-1976
    Memos regarding endowment principal
  - Mellon/Symphony Orchestras - National Arts Stabilization Fund, 1966-1988 (Box 19, Folder 174)
  - Symphony Orchestras - Ford, Mellon, and Findings, 1976-1982 (Box 19, Folder 175)
  - Symphony Orchestra Program - Trust Distribution and Control Sheets, 1975-1976 (Box 19, Folder 176)
    Contains:
    Orchestras and Proportion Shares
    Control Sheets
    Instructions Distribution of Trust
  - Symphony Orchestra Program - Endowment Funds Report, 1972-1976 (Box 19, Folder 177)
    New York Philharmonic
    The Philadelphia Orchestra
    San Francisco Symphony Orchestra
    Milwaukee Symphony Orchestra
    Utah Symphony
    Toledo Symphony Orchestra
    Wichita Symphony Orchestra
    Shreveport Symphony
  - Symphony Orchestra Program - Clippings, Correspondence with Symphonies, Budget Information, 1953-1981 (Box 20, Folder 178)
  - Mellon Symphony Program Analysis, 1986-1988 (Box 20, Folder 179)
  - Symphony Orchestra Program - Annex and Exhibit Files, 1973-1976 (Box 20, Folder 180)
  - Symphony Orchestras - Annexed to Agreements, Terms of Grant, Handwritten Notes, 1966-1975 (Box 20, Folder 181)
  - Mellon/Symphony Orchestra Program - Addresses and Staff, Drafts, and Calculation of Current Position (3 folders), 1974-1979 (Box 20, Folder 182-184)
  - Symphony Orchestra Program - Quarterly Payments, 1971-1978 (Box 20, Folder 185)
    Spreadsheets - yearly sheets, summary spreadsheets for all years, and addendum sheets
  - Symphony and Orchestra Program #1 - 1-10 - KH, 1972-1986 (Box 20, Folder 186)
    Includes financial reviews from various fiscal years in the 1960s, '70s, and '80s for:
    1. American Symphony
    2. Atlanta Symphony
    3. Baltimore Symphony
    4. Birmingham Symphony Association